Guide to the Richard Earl Fikes Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Richard Earl Fikes papers
1965-2004
SC0881
Fikes, Richard E.
20 Linear feet
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Biographical/Historical note
Richard Earl Fikes is Professor (Research) Emeritus in the Computer Science department of Stanford University.
Richard has a long and distinguished record as an innovative leader in the development of techniques for effectively representing and using knowledge in computer systems. He is best known as co-developer of the STRIPS (Stanford Research Institute Problem Solver) automatic planning system, KIF (Knowledge Interchange Format), the Ontolingua ontology representation language and Web-based ontology development environment, the OKBC (Open Knowledge Base Connectivity) API for knowledge servers, and IntelliCorp's KEE (Knowledge Engineering Environment) system.
At Stanford, he leaded projects focused on developing large-scale distributed repositories of computer-interpretable knowledge, collaborative development of multi-use ontologies, enabling technology for the Semantic Web, reasoning methods applicable to large-scale knowledge bases, and knowledge-based technology for intelligence analysts.
He was principal investigator of major projects for DARPA in the High Performance Knowledge Base (HPKB) program, the Rapid Knowledge Formation (RKF) program, the DARPA (Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency) Agent Markup Language (DAML) program, the UltraLog program, and the Rapid Design Exploration and Optimization (RaDEO) program.
Richard was born on October 4, 1942 in San Antontio, Texas. He received his B.A. in Mathematics with honors from the University of Texas at Austin in 1963, his M.A. in Mathematics from the University of Texas at Austin in 1965, and his Ph.D. in Computer Science from Carnegie Mellon University in 1968.
Richard was a Research Associate in the Computer Science Department at the Carnegie-Mellon University from 1968 to 1969. He worked as a Senior Mathematician in SRI (Stanford Research Institute) from 1969-1976. He was a member of Research Staff in Xerox Palo Alto Research Center from 1976 to 1983. He joined IntelliCorp Inc. in 1986 as the Director of Research and Development in 1983 and was the Vice President of Research when he left the company in 1987. He started in Price Waterhouse Technology Center in 1987 as a Principal Scientist and was the Chief Scientist in 1991 when he left the company. He served as the Associate Director, Heuristic Programming Project, Knowledge Systems Laboratory, Stanford University in 1991. He was a Professor (Research), Computer Science Department from 1991 to 2006.
Richard was elected a Founding Fellow of the American Association for Artificial Intelligence (AAAI) in 1990. He also chaired, co-chaired, organized, or served on the program committee of numerous professional gatherings such as AAAI86 and IJCAI89.
Access Terms
SRI International; Stanford University. Computer Science Department.; Xerox Corporation. Palo Alto Research Center.; Knowledge representation (Information theory)
Collection Contents
- Correspondence, 1969-2005; Series 1
  - Letters and memos dating from, 1969 to 1974, and 1981 to 2003 (Box 27)
    - Letters, 1969-1974 (Box 27)
    - Letters, 1981-1983 (Box 13)
    - Letters, 1983-1987 (Box 16)
    - Letters, 1987-1989 (Box 19)
    - Letters, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
    - Letters, 1991-2003 (Box 22)
    - Memo, 1987-1991 (Box 16)
    - Memo, 1987-1991 (Box 16)
- Graduate Studies, 1996; Series 2
  - University of Texas at Austin (Box 1)
    - Master thesis by Richard Fikes at the University of Texas at Austin, 1965 (Box 1)
    - SYCK – 63, A FORTRAN-63 SYNTAX CHECKER, 1965 (Box 1)
    - Misc. Projects at the University of Texas at Austin:, 1963-1965 (Box 1)
      POLSOL: A Heuristic Program for Solving Polyominoe Problems, 1965 Storing Programs in a Processed Form, 1965 Student Program Evaluating Program, 1964 A Human Arithmetic Stimulation, 1963 Language Learning (Project AMOS), n.d. A Phase Structure Grammar for LIPL, 1964 SYCK: A System for Checking the Syntax of FORTRAN-63 Programs, 1965 Contingency Tables and Association Coefficients, 1965 Card-To-Tape (088 to 164), n.d. Paper Tape To Magnetic Tape, 1964
  - Carnegie-Mellon University
    - Ph. D. Qualifying Examinations (Box 1)
    - Published papers at Carnegie-Mellon University, 1968, 1970 (Box 1)
      REF-ARF: A System for Solving Problems Stated as Procedures, 1970 Stating Problems as Procedures to a General Problem Solving Problem, 1968 Steps toward a general-purpose time-sharing system using large capacity core storage and TSS/360 – Proceedings: 1968 ACM National Conference, 1968 Steps toward a general-purpose time-sharing system using large capacity core storage and TSS/360 – Progress report, 1968
    - A Heuristic Program for Solving Problems Stated as Nondeterministic Procedures, 1968 (1 of 2) (Box 2)
    - A Heuristic Program for Solving Problems Stated as Nondeterministic Procedures, 1968 (2 of 2) (Box 2)
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (1 of 6): (Box 3)
      MSCB, MSCB-2, SORT, MAGIC, CRYPT-1, 3 COINS, QUEE, HYPO, n.d.
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (2 of 6):, 1969 (Box 4)
      Hypothesis Formation, 1969 Monkey, 1969 Waterjng, 1969 John and Mike, 1969 Confusion of Patents, n.d. 8 Queens, 1969 Tennis, 1969 Instant Insanity, 1969 Picnic, 1969 Magic Square, 1969 SORT, 1968 Bill Mann’s Problem, 1969
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (3 of 6):, 1968-1969 (Box 5)
      Magic, 1969 Loveland, 1968 Tower of Hunoi, 1968
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (4 of 6):, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
      Peek, 1968 Htower I, II, III, IV, V, VI, VII, VIII, XI, X, 1969
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (5 of 6):, 1968-1969 (Box 7)
      Cross Roads I, II, 1969 Tower of Hanoi (Heuristic sear formulation), 1969 Missionaries, 1969 Cross Roads, 1968 Escape, 1969
    - Computer program listings at the Carnegie-Mellon University (6 of 6): (Box 8)
      Load source09 onto EXPREF, 1969 STRIPS.QA3: TRANSLATED QA3 + STRQA3 MDLFNS.TRAB;4, MODEL.;2, LRNOPS.;5, U2STRIPS.;, OTSTRIPS.;6, Missionaries & Cannibals, 1969 Program Writer, 1969 ADSTRIPS.;2, EHSTRIPS.;7, INSTRIPS.;, INVE, n.d. Monkey, n.d.
- Private Sector, Series 3
  - SRI International
    - Published papers at SRI (1 of 7):, 1971-1973 (Box 9)
      Learning and Executing Generalized Robot Plans, 1972 Knowledge Representation in Automatic Planning Systems, 1977 STRIPS: A New Approach to the Application of Theorem Proving to Problem Solving, 1971 Some New Directions in Robot Problem Solving, 1972 Themes in Automatic Problem Solving, 1973 A Network-Based Knowledge Representation and its Natural Deduction System, n.d. Monitored Execution of Robot Plans Produced by STRIPS, 1972
    - Published papers at SRI (2 of 7):, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      Augmentation Aids for Solving Constraint Problems Interactively, n.d. A LISP Implementation of BIP, 1970 STRIPS: A New Approach to the Application of Theorem Proving to Problem Solving, 1970 Failure Tests and Goals in Plans, 1971 Monitored Execution of Robot plans Produced by STRIPS, 1971 STRIPS: A New Approach to the Application of Theorem Proving to Problem Solving, 1971
    - Published papers at SRI (3 of 7):, 1970-1971 (Box 9)
      Research and Applications – Artificial Intelligence (Semiannual Progress Report: 1970-1971 Research and Applications – Artificial Intelligence (Final Report: 1970-1971)
    - Published papers at SRI (4 of 7):, 1972 (Box 9)
      Learning and Executing Generalized Robot Plans, 1972 Some New Directions in Robot Problem Solving, 1972 A Set of Transportation Tasks for Factotem (Draft), 1972
    - Published papers at SRI (5 of 7):, 1973-1974 (Box 9)
      Artificial Intelligence - Research and Applications – Progress Report: April 1973- April 1974
    - Published papers at SRI (6 of 7):, 1973-1975 (Box 10)
      Themes in Automatic Problem Solving, 1973 Plan for a Computer-Based Consultant System, 1974 Deductive Retrieval Mechanisms fro State Description Models, 1975 An Interactive Management Support System for Planning, Control, and Analysis, 1975
    - Published papers at SRI (7 of 7):, 1976-1977 (Box 10)
      Knowledge Representation in Automatic Planning Systems, 1976 Large File Management Information Systems, 1976 A Network-Based Knowledge Representation and its Natural Deduction System, 1977
    - Expense reports (1970 – 1974) / Resume (Box 10)
  - Xerox Palo Alto Research Center
    - Research Papers at Xerox Palo Alto Research Center: (Box 10)
      A Commitment-Based Framework for Describing Informal Cooperative Work, 1982 A Commitment-Based Model of Office Work for Expert Office Systems [Slide], 1982 Automating the Problem Solving in Procedural Office Work, 1981 A Representation System User Interface for Knowledge Base Designers, 1982 Odyssey: A Knowledge-Based Assistant, 1981 On Supporting the Use of Procedures in Office Work, 1980 RABBIT: Cognitive Science in Interface Design, n.d. A Functionally-Specified Representation Systems, 1983 Functional Specification of a New Knowledge Representation Implementation [Draft], n.d.
    - KRYPTON (1 of 3), 1982-1983 (Box 10)
      A Functional Approach to Knowledge Representation, 1983 / Integrating Terminology and Assertion, 1983 / Related materials, 1982-1983
    - KRYPTON (2 of 3), 1982-1983 (Box 10)
    - KRYPTON (3 of 3), 1982-1983 (Box 10)
    - Odyssey: A Knowledge-Based Assistant Screen Prints and Screen Shots, 1981 (Box 11)
    - Odyssey: A Knowledge-Based Assistant Drafts, 1979-1980 (Box 11)
    - Odyssey: A Knowledge-Based Assistant Related Materials (1 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - Odyssey: A Knowledge-Based Assistant Related Materials (2 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 11)
    - Bluebonnet: 8200 Lisp Interface (1 of 2), 1983 (Box 11)
    - Bluebonnet: 8200 Lisp Interface (2 of 2), 1983 (Box 11)
    - Enterprise (1 of 2), 1981 (Box 12)
    - Enterprise (2 of 2), 1981 (Box 12)
    - Some Preliminary Thoughts on Expert Office Systems, Forms, KRL1, etc., 1976-1978 (Box 13)
    - Personal Calendar System / Notes, 1977-1980 (Box 12)
    - T-Box, Symbol Table, and Others, 1980-1982 (Box 12)
    - Xerox Administrations, 1976-1983 (Box 13)
    - Miscellaneous Activity in Xerox: (Box 12)
      Decision Support Systems Journal, 1984 / AAAI 83, 1983 / IEEE Computer Magazine Survey, n.d. / Xerox CSL AI Planning, 1978-1979 / Xerox Softball, 1981-1982
  - IntelliCorp Inc.
    - Publications at IntelliCorp. (Box 13)
      An Assertion and Retrieval Interface for a Frame-Based Representation system, 1985 / The Role of Frame-Based Representation in Reasoning, 1985 Market-like Task Scheduling in Distributed Computing Environments, 1986
    - Tools for Building Knowledge Systems: Representation and Acquisition, 1985 (Box 13)
    - OPUS, 1987 / Semantically Sound Inheritance for a Formally Defined Language with Defaults, n.d. (Box 13)
    - KEE [Knowledge Engineering Environment] transparencies (1 of 5), 1986 (Box 14)
    - KEE [Knowledge Engineering Environment] transparencies (2 of 5), 1986 (Box 14)
    - KEE [Knowledge Engineering Environment] transparencies (3 of 5), 1986 (Box 14)
    - KEE [Knowledge Engineering Environment] transparencies (4 of 5), 1986 (Box 14)
    - KEE [Knowledge Engineering Environment] transparencies (5 of 5), 1986 (Box 14)
    - Frame Based Representation (1 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 15)
    - Frame Based Representation (2 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 15)
    - Frame Based Representation (3 of 3), 1985-1986 (Box 15)
    - DARPA [Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency] (1 of 2), 1987 (Box 15)
    - DARPA [Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency] (2 of 2), 1987 (Box 15)
    - Other Projects at IntelliCorp. (Box 15)
      KSRD, 1985 / Truth Maintenance, n.d. / Recursive Unites, 1984 / Expert Systems, 1986 / The Framer’s Dilemma, n.d.
    - IntelliCorp. Corporate Presentations (1 of 2), 1983-1987 (Box 16)
    - IntelliCorp. Corporate Presentations (2 of 2), 1983-1987 (Box 16)
    - Note Books, 1983-1987 (Box 13)
    - IntelliCorp. Admin. / Design Notes, 1983-1987 (Box 16)
  - Price Waterhouse Technology Centre
    - Business Understander Project (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 17)
    - Business Understander Project (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 17)
    - Risk Assessment System (1 of 2), 1990 (Box 17)
    - Risk Assessment System (2 of 2), 1990 (Box 17)
    - Beyond the Current Plateau – Knowledge System Futures, 1988 (Box 17)
    - Modeling and Analyzing Businesses: A High Payoff Challenge for AI, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Knowledge-Based Systems Program, n.d. (Box 18)
    - Using New technologies in Auditing, 1990 (Box 18)
    - Estimating Project Cost, 1990 (Box 18)
    - JOSIE, 1990 / AI & Software Engineering, 1990 / International Funds Transfer, 1989 (Box 18)
    - Other Projects at Price Waterhouse (Box 19)
      International Tax Advisory System, 1990 / Prototyping Knowledge-Based Systems, 1990 / Saying More with Frames: Slots as Classes, 1992 / Information Systems Research Experimental Systems, n.d. / Straw Man Knowledge Representation Interlingua, n.d.
    - Diagnostic Reasoning Template - Coherent Thought, 1989 (Box 18)
    - Overseas Trips (Price Waterhouse):, 1988-1989 (Box 19)
      Australia Trip, 1989 / Japan AI Study, 1988 / Hong Kong Talk, 1988
    - Note Books, n.d. (Box 19)
    - Expenses / Budgets / Timesheets / Hiring / Workstation Purchase Request, 1987-1991 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous activity at Price Waterhouse: (Box 19)
      Tech Centre Talk, 1989 / Book Review, 1987 / New Science Associates Inc.’s 3rd Annual AI Forum, 1989
  - YY Software Corp. Board of Advisors Meetings, 1998-1999 (Box 27)
- Stanford University, Series 4
  - Knowledge Systems Laboratory
    - KSL Overview Slides, 1991 (Box 22)
    - Research papers (1 of 2) (Box 23)
      Semantics of “Knowledge Sharing”, 1993 / A Declarative Formalization of Knowledge Translation, 1995 / The Role of Reversible Grammars in Translating Between Representation Languages, 1994 / Lifting in Propositional Theories of Context, 1996 / STRIPS, a retrospective, 1993 / Test, Generation, and Explanation of Control Procedures for Configurable Systems, 1993 / A proof markup language for Semantic Web services, 2005 / Automated model selection from simulation based on relevance reasoning, 1997
    - Research papers (2 of 2) (Box 23)
      The Stanford KSL Knowledge Base Merging Critical Component Experiment, 1999 / An Axiomatic Semantics for RDF, RDF/S, and DAML+OIL, 2001 / Explaining Results from Information Retrieval and Integration, n.d. / Extracting Assumptions from Incomplete Data, n.d. / Semantics of Translation, n.d. / The DARPA Knowledge Sharing Effort: Progress Report, n.d. / JTP: A System Architecture and Component Library for Hybrid Reason, n.d.
    - US ARL Federated Laboratory Proposal “Red Team Review” (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 23)
    - US ARL Federated Laboratory Proposal “Red Team Review” (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 23)
    - DME [Device Modeling Environment], n.d. (Box 23)
    - KIF [Knowledge Interchange Format], 1990-1992
    - Model-Enabled Control of Reconfigurable Hybrid Systems, 1998 (Box 24)
    - SIMNET Network and Protocols, 1991 (Box 24)
    - SMART [System for Manufacturing Using Advanced Representation Technology], (1 of 4), 1993-1994 (Box 24)
    - SMART [System for Manufacturing Using Advanced Representation Technology], (2 of 4), 1993-1994 (Box 24)
    - SMART [System for Manufacturing Using Advanced Representation Technology], (3 of 4) (Box 24)
    - SMART [System for Manufacturing Using Advanced Representation Technology], (4 of 4), 1993-1994 (Box 24)
    - MADE [Manufacturing Automation and Design Engineering] (1 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 25)
    - MADE [Manufacturing Automation and Design Engineering] (2 of 3) (Box 25)
    - MADE [Manufacturing Automation and Design Engineering] (3 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 25)
    - “Knowledge-Assisted Software Engineering (KASE) and Development of a KASE Environment”, 1992 (Box 25)
    - Novell Intelligence from Semi-Structured Knowledge, 2002-2006 (Box 25)
    - NIE [National-Scale Information Enterprises], n.d. (Box 26)
    - How Things Work (project details, email correspondence, presentations, financials, supporting documents) (1 of 3), 1993-1994 (Box 27)
    - How Things Work (project details, email correspondence, presentations, financials, supporting documents) (2 of 3), 1991-1994 (Box 27)
    - How Things Work (project details, email correspondence, presentations, financials, supporting documents) (3 of 3), 1991-1994 (Box 27)
    - HPKB (project information, presentations, papers), 1994 (Box 27)
    - KDI [Knowledge and Distribution Intelligence], 1998 (Box 31)
    - Other Projects in Stanford (1 of 8) (Box 26)
      Explainable Knowledge Aggregation from Multiple Heterogeneous Information Sources, 2004 / Explainable Integrated Learning Proposal, n.d. / Ultra*long, 2000
    - Other Projects in Stanford (2 of 8) (Box 26)
      Real-World Hybrid Reasoning with Large-Scale Heterogeneous Knowledge Bases, 2004 / Shared Knowledge Representation Language, 1992
    - Other Projects in Stanford (3 of 8) (Box 26)
      KANI [Knowledge Associates for Novell Intelligence], 2004 / NIMD [Novel Intelligence for Massive Data], 2002 / Global Knowledge Network Project, 2002
    - Other Projects in Stanford (4 of 8) (Box 26)
      Center for Information Technology, 1993 / Testing, Generating, and Explaining Control Procedures for Reactive Hybrid Systems, 1993 / Technology for Developing Network-based Information Brokers, 1997 / Flexible Item Identification to Support Advanced Logistics, 1997
    - Other Projects in Stanford (5 of 8) (Box 26)
      Complex System Modeling, Analysis and Simulation Project, 1999 / Technology for DAML-Based Services, 2002 / Cognitive Information Processing Technology for the Enduring Personal Cognitive Assistant, 2003 / Mapping Allen-Expressions to Time-Slices in OWL, n.d. / KDD, n.d. / Global InfoBase, 1999
    - Other Projects in Stanford (6 of 8):, 1991-1992 (Box 31)
      Research on Multi-Use Knowledge Bases, 1991 / Shared Knowledge Representation Language, 1991 / Shared Knowledge Base Technology for Re-Engineering Problem Program, 1991 / Research on Knowledge-Based Technology for Engineering Design, 1991 / Research on Knowledge-Based Technology for Engineering Applications, 1991 / Development of a Reusable Knowledge Base for Space Applications, 1992 /
    - Other Projects in Stanford (7 of 8):, 1999-2001 (Box 31)
      Intelligent Systems Initiative, 1999 / Creating, Maintaining, and Integrating Understandable Knowledge Bases, 2000 / Research in Intelligent Systems, 2001
    - Other Projects in Stanford (8 of 8):, 1992, 1995 (Box 31)
      Research on Intelligent Systems for Science and Engineering Applications, 1992 / Computer Science Challenges – Opportunities in Support Multidisciplinary Research, 1995
    - Proposal of Collaboration with KSL, n.d. (Box 27)
  - Teaching and Administration
    - Stanford Teaching CS106, Examination, Problems, computer program listings, 1970 (Box 21)
    - Stanford Teaching CS105.2, computer program listings, handouts, 1973 (Box 21)
    - Stanford Teaching CS105, computer program listings, 1973 (Box 21)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (1 of 4), 1998 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (2 of 4), 1998 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (3 of 4), 1998 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 Lecture Presentation Slides (4 of 4), 1998 (Box 20)
    - CS 222 World Fact Book Project, 1997 (Box 21)
    - CS 222 Exams, 1997, 2004; Home Work, 1998 (Box 21)
    - Teaching Evaluations, 1997-2004 (Box 31)
    - PhD Qualifying Examination, 1997 (Box 21)
    - Stanford Administrations (1 of 3): (Box 21)
      Meetings (agenda and minutes) / Research Administration Advisory Group report, 1994 / Consulting Faculty Activity report, 1990-1991 / A Vision of Computer Science in the Next Decade, 1994 / KSL Financials, 2006 / International WWW Consortium Participation Agreement, 2001
    - Stanford Administrations (2 of 3): (Box 21)
      University Oral Examinations, 1991-2000 / French Students work for KSL, 1992-1993 / “HCI Graduate Research Traineeship” proposal, 1993 / “Diagrammatic Reasoning in Program Solving” proposal, 1992 / “Internet World Wide Web Based Variable Fidelity Simulator” proposal, 1995 / Copyright and Patent Agreement, 1991 / Consulting Agreement, 1998
    - Stanford Administrations (3 of 3): (Box 31)
      Job Applications (1992, 2006) / Resignation Notices
- Professional Organization Activity, Series 5
  - Conference on Office Information Systems, 1982 (Box 13)
  - AAAI-86 Tutorial Materials [American Association for Artificial Intelligence] (1 of 3), 1986 (Box 28)
  - AAAI-86 Tutorial Materials [American Association for Artificial Intelligence] (2 of 3), 1986 (Box 28)
  - AAAI-86 Tutorial Materials [American Association for Artificial Intelligence] (3 of 3), 1986 (Box 28)
  - AAAI Spring Symposium Series, papers, correspondence, etc. (1 of 2), 1989 (Box 28)
  - AAAI Spring Symposium Series, papers, correspondence, etc. (2 of 2), 1989 (Box 28)
  - IJCAI [International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence], Conference papers (1 of 4), 1989 (Box 29)
  - IJCAI [International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence], Conference papers (2 of 4), 1989 (Box 29)
  - IJCAI [International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence], Conference papers (3 of 4), 1989
  - IJCAI [International Joint Conferences on Artificial Intelligence], Conference papers (4 of 4), 1989 (Box 29)
  - Second International Conference on Principles of Knowledge Representation KR ’91 (1 of 2) (correspondence, conference paper, paper reviews), 1991 (Box 30)
  - Second International Conference on Principles of Knowledge Representation KR ’91 (2 of 2) (correspondence, conference paper, paper reviews), 1991 (Box 30)
  - AAAI 1987 / DARPA Planning Workshop 1987 (presentations, draft presentations, etc.) (Box 30)
  - Other Conferences, symposiums, forums and workshops (correspondence, programs, and presentations) (1 of 3): (Box 28)
    Artificial Intelligence and Advanced Computer Technology Conference AI 1988 / The Second International Symposium on Expert Systems in Business, Finance and Accounting 1989 / Fifth Canadian Conference on Auditing and Computer Technology 1990 / National Conference on Artificial Intelligence 1990
  - Other Conferences, symposiums, forums and workshops (correspondence, programs, and presentations) (2 of 3): (Box 29)
    The Sixth IEEE Conference on Artificial Intelligence Applications, 1990 / Decision Making, Cognitive Science and Accounting, 1991 / Workshop on “Intelligent Information System Development Tools, Environments and Methodologies”, 1991 / AAAI 1991 Spring Symposium / AAAI 1999 Fall Symposium / IIS Workshop #1, n.d. / Rockwell Artificial Intelligence Technical Panel (1992) / Quintus Forum, n.d. / Artificial Intelligence and Advanced Computer Technology Conference AI 1986
  - Other Conferences, symposiums, forums and workshops (correspondence, programs, and presentations) (3 of 3): (Box 30)
    KL-ONE Workshop, 1981 / Knowledge Representation Workshop, 1983 / Expert System Tools Workshop, 1986
- Audio-Visual and Electronic Materials, Series 6
  - Slides (Box 32)
  - Photographs (Box 32)
  - IBM Flowcharting Template (Box 32)
  - Floppy disks (3 1/2"), 50 computer media (Box 32)